vector.com 2005-04-05

# Vector ESP - Privacy Policy

**Privacy Policy**

_ Version 10/01/2004_

Vector ESP is committed to protecting your privacy. We have designed our sites so you may visit them without revealing any personal information.  However, we may ask you to provide information that personally identifies you in certain circumstances, including for example when you register for an event, request information or join one of our email notification services. Vector ESP’s Web sites may contain links to sites controlled by, and pages maintained by, independent third parties. Vector ESP does not control the use of personal information provided to such third parties and such information will be governed by the applicable third party’s privacy policy.

** Why does Vector ESP collect information? **

  1. To help us personalize Website content to you. 
  2. To help improve the value of the information provided on our site to you.
  3. To alert you to Vector ESP’s product and service offerings, events, and other new or updated information. 
  4. To send information regarding upcoming events, training classes, products or service offerings to you through the US Mail or via electronic mail.
  5. To evaluate job applicants in the case of online job application submissions.
  6. To request your voluntary participation in research surveys
  7. To provide you online access to your account information

As mentioned previously, Vector ESP has designed its sites so that you may visit them without revealing any personal information.  However, in some instances, it is necessary for Vector ESP to collect information on you in order to efficiently perform the service you may have requested. 

At times you may receive promotions, specials, newsletters or other pertinent information from Vector ESP. If you prefer not to receive those, you can opt out by sending us an email at [remove@vector.com](mailto:remove@vector.com) or by mentioning it directly to your account manager. 

Vector ESP is committed to providing all customers with a world-class experience. In order to measure how well we are doing and to better understand how we can continually improve our product offerings and our ability to meet your unique requirements, from time-to-time we may contact you by phone or e-mail and solicit your participation in research. Your participation is voluntary and you may request to remove yourself from future efforts of this kind. 

** What information does Vector ESP collect?**

Some of our services require you to register for an account.  In such instances, Vector ESP may request personal data such as your first and last name, your company name, your physical addresses, your telephone number, a password, and your email address.  For other services, such as online purchases, we may request credit card or other payment information which we maintain in encrypted form on secure servers. 

** How do I update my information?**

In order to update your information, you can either request a change from a Vector ESP employee or you may do it on your own online by visiting our site and logging in to your account.  Once there, you can access your “My Account” page and will find a “My Profile/Password” link that allows you to edit your information. 

** How does Vector ESP secure my information? **

As an existing customer, you have the opportunity to view and purchase quotes online, review your invoices, view and update support contracts as well as access your account team’s contact information.  Access to your personal information is restricted within our company to provide maximum security.  Only authorized programming personnel are permitted to see your password. If you forget your password, you can request a new one be created and emailed to you. Only authorized sales, customer service and accounting personnel are permitted access to your account and credit card information, which is stored in encrypted form on secure servers.

We employ powerful 128-bit encryption technology and Secure Socket Layers (SSL) in all areas where your personal identity is required. 

** Use of Cookies?**

Certain portions of the Vector ESP website may use cookies to enhance your experience. Cookies are pieces of information used for record-keeping and navigation-tracking purposes. Use of cookies makes web-surfing easier by performing certain functions such as saving your username, passwords or your personal preferences regarding your use of the particular website. Many consider the use of cookies to be an industry standard. Your browser is probably set to accept cookies. However, if you would prefer not to receive cookies, you can alter the configuration of your browser to refuse cookies. If you choose to have your browser refuse cookies, it is possible that some areas of the Vector ESP website will not function properly when you view them. Vector ESP will never use cookies as a means of infringing upon your privacy, but will only use cookies as a means of enhancing your experience with this website.

** IP Addresses**

We collect an IP address from all visitors to the Vector ESP websites. Your IP address is used to help diagnose problems with our server, to analyze trends, administer the site, track user's movement, and gather broad demographic information about aggregate site use.  IP addresses ARE NOT linked to personally identifiable information. 

** Protection of Your Personal Information**

VECTOR ESP DOES NOT SELL PERSONAL INFORMATION TO ANY OUTSIDE SOURCES.  Additionally, Vector ESP does not exchange, trade, give or relinquish personal information to any outside sources except in some instances for the following purposes: i) to complete a transaction that was initiated by you ii) to co-market to you with a strategic partner of Vector ESP, or iii) to respond to subpoenas, court orders, or other legal processes, as required by law, or to establish or exercise our legal rights or defend against legal claims.  Additionally, your personal and account information may also be disclosed in connection with a sale of some or all of our business or a merger with another company. 

** Your Acceptance of These Terms**

By using this site, you signify your consent to the Vector ESP Internet Privacy Policy. We reserve the right, at our discretion, to change, modify, add, or remove portions from this policy at any time. Please check this page periodically for changes.  To see previous copies of this privacy policy, please visit [ www.vector.com/privacy_archive.asp](http://www.vector.com/privacy_archive.asp).

** Questions**

If you choose not to provide personal, or other, information, you can still use the majority of the Vector ESP Web sites. If for some reason you believe Vector ESP has not adhered to these principles, please notify us by e-mail at _ [remove@vector.com](mailto:remove@vector.com)_, and we will use commercially reasonable efforts to promptly determine and correct the problem.

If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this website, or your dealings with this website, please contact:

** Vector ESP, ****a division of MTM Technologies, Inc.**  
12600 Northborough Dr., Suite 200  
Houston, TX 77067  
281.453.4500  

© 2000-2004 Vector ESP
